by first talking about the the global
setup once again. Mark Franklin, deputy
head of multiasset solutions Asia at
Manual Life Investments is with us now.
Mark, good morning. Thanks very much for
joining us on the show today. So, you
know, I just want to understand uh what
kind of shifts if at all uh you have
planned or you have executed in in the
strategy in your portfolios since this
big event happened, this uh you know
window of conversation between China and
the US, the lowering of tariffs and at
least this 90-day pause that we've got.
I mean we've seen that play out in
markets right we've seen some tactical
money shift to China we've seen the cool
off in gold we've seen in general
commodities start to move higher but as
an asset manager uh what are the changes
if any that you are looking at now
good morning well if you look at the the
V-shaped experience that equity markets
have given us over the last few weeks
it's created a number of opportunities
the first opportunity is to increasingly
diversify our global equities exposure
so to lean a bit more on those regions
ex the US. So you mentioned Asia to some
extent Europe and Japan as well. So
we're looking for more of a breadth of
participation which founds itself on the
idea that valuations increasingly will
matter. Risk premier will matter
particularly if markets pursue a more
volatile choppier experience over the
rest of the year. The second thing that
we've done in more recent times is the
acknowledgement as a result of the the
thaw in the trade dynamics, the
relationship between the US and China in
particular. It sort of takes the worstc
case scenario for the macro outlook off
the table for the time being, not
permanently so. And what that means in
practice is that the market's focus will
shift increasingly on the next policy
initiative of the Trump administration
which will be tax cuts uh spending plans
which are generally expected to be
somewhat reflationary. The consequence
of that is that we're starting to
lighten up a little bit on our bond
exposure, particularly US treasuries,
because the the economic risks are being
somewhat priced out again and the focus
will be more on a reflationary policy
mix in terms of the potential and so not
just the curve steepening, but the whole
of the yield curve starting to move
higher as a more benign growth outlook
becomes the base case. Again, of course,
we do recognize that narratives can
subsequently shift again, but that's
what we've been doing in most recent
times. It's just lightening up a little
bit on those more defensive exposures.
Mark, hi, morning. Let's talk about
India. The many factors which were
supportive of India over the last few
months, whether it's lower dollar, lower
crude prices, trade headwinds on uh
China, they've all reversed. So while
India in a way is still relatively
insulated from the disruptions that
we're seeing has the sheen come off the
Indian equity markets through your mind.
We also have to bring into the equation
the geopolitical dynamics as well.
Thankfully looks like things are paused
there cooling down that was perhaps
something which represented a bit of a a
tangential risk to investor appetite for
Indian equities. So with that put to one
side for the time being I think that
foreign investors are taking a fresh
look at India again not just for the
construct of the economy and markets
being somewhat more domestically
oriented but the recognition that
positioning particularly amongst foreign
investors is somewhat lighter now than
it was 6 months ago and therefore
there's the potential for a
re-engagement and for overseas flows to
come back into the market. We are
somewhat more constructive on Indian
equities at this point in time. But we
do recognize that we have to be somewhat
price sensitive given that valuation
multiples never really got that
discounted both relative to history but
also relative to other markets as well.
Hi Mark, good morning and good to see
you Ben. You know you had uh you had
pointed out that the Indian markets are
not particularly cheap. So I think this
time correction, price correction, I
think that will uh you know hold well.
But in terms of global markets, where is
your preference right now? You know the
US markets, there were good amount of
longs that were added in the initial
part of the calendar year which got
unbound. So give and take everything.
What's your top global equity market
that you're looking at? We take a
barbell approach at the moment. As I
mentioned earlier, a more diversified
global equities portfolio than we would
have run maybe six months ago. And so on
one side of that barbell is looking for
markets which are somewhat discounted
relative to fundamentals and also give
you a nice total return potential not
just from capital returns but also from
income. And a market that does fall into
that category is is the UK large caps
very discounted market a good dividend
profile and not a reflection of the me
do domestic UK economy which we know has
somewhat of a challenged picture. So
that's an example of discounted
valuations that we like. We also think
that Asian equities also fall into that
category as well. And then on the other
side of the equation is still looking
for those businesses which give you
franchise value thematic growth
potential. In that context, we like
cyber security. Um we also like defense
technology as well. So these are sectors
that are not inexpensive. They're
somewhat premium valuations, but we can
see with a degree of confidence that
over the next several years there's
going to be a nice compound growth
potential. And so the market will
eventually reward that because of the
delivery of earnings growth. So
combination of earnings growth, theatic
strength alongside those discounted
parts of global equity markets which
gives us a nice blend.
All right, Mark. We'll uh then leave it
on that note. Thank you very much. Uh
appreciate the perspective that you've
given us today. Thank you very much for
joining in. Well, uh, that's one